I've been using the iron bull 6in
reinforced lifting belt over the past
few weeks my favorite things about it
are the nylon build since it's going to
allow you to stay pretty mobile for
explosive movements but since the back
is reinforced it's going to create
optimal support for your lower back and
then also you know this velcro strap
paired with the self-locking roller
Buckle right here is going to prevent
the belt from becoming loose mid workout
we got a lot to talk about today so
let's get right to
it
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the ironbull 6-in
reinforced lifting belt info review now
I'm going to talk my head off into this
camera today but specifically we're
going to be talking about some money
some pros and cons and then of course
who should or maybe should not purchase
this lifting belt but per usual before I
do all of that I got to let y'all know
that we've reviewed a whole lot of other
lifting belts on barb. comom and we went
ahead and made a best list of all of our
top picks so if you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barbend
best lifting belts it's going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the
best okay so before I start talking
about you know what I like about this
belt let's talk about lifting belts in
general all right so lifting belts are
going to help you create intraabdominal
pressure by you allowing you to have an
external source to break against and
this is really going to come in handy as
you start lifting heavy weight and could
you know potentially help you lift
heavier weight then also reduce you know
your chances of injury now there's a lot
of different styles of belts okay so
obviously this is a nylon belt and so
there's plenty of leather belts and a
lot of thickness going on as well so it
kind of gets confusing when you know for
some people when it comes to finding the
right belt for them really it boils down
to your style of training okay so
typically a nylon belt such as this one
is going to be more ideal for you know
expl explosive lifts Crossfit Olympic
weightlifting where you're doing you
know hang cleans you know power cleans
clean and jerk the snatch all those kind
of movements because they're going to
allow you to stay more mobile and
they're typically you know not as thick
as a leather belt so with leather belts
it's going to be mainly focused around
you know powerlifting squatting and
deadlifting specifically so with a
leather belt you can either have you
know 7 mm thick 10 mm thick or 13 mm
thick so the thicker the belt is the
more support that you're going to be
able to have and leather belts tend to
provide more support than nylon belts in
general just because they're more rigid
okay so with this one right here
remember you do have that reinforced
backing so this is about this is quarter
of an inch thick so it's a little over 6
mm so you can definitely still use this
belt for your powerlifting movements but
because it is nylon it's going to allow
you you know like I said earlier stay
pretty mobile and be pretty explosive
for those Olympic weightlifting
movements and Crossfit as well so if
you're you know looking to kind of get a
a belt that's kind of Best of Both
Worlds something like this is actually
really solid especially you know once
again because you do have this
reinforced backing right here so bottom
line definitely just prioritize your
style of training when it comes to
looking for a belt that's you know going
to coincide with your training right
okay so with this belt specifically I
really enjoy this reinforced backing
right here it does allow it to you know
stay pretty stiff in the back and that's
a really good thing you know especially
deadlifting and squatting where you know
you are putting a lot of stress on your
back this is going to be really nice and
you know prevent help you prevent you
getting hurt okay so also really really
do enjoy belts like this that have this
velcro strap and the self-locking roller
right here it's going to allow you to
get a really tight fit you know around
your belly button right here which is
where you want that belt to be it's
going to allow it to stay really nice
and and tight and snug and prevent it
from you know popping loose on you mid
workout you definitely do not want that
this belt is also available in five
different sizes from extra small to
double XL so pretty much every lifter
you know can find a belt that's going to
suit them and then also it's available
in six different colors which is pretty
cool too so you can kind of get swaggy
with it a little bit I guess you could
say and then also really enjoy the taper
design right here all right so in the
back you have a 6-in wide profile it's
going to create you know optimal you
know surface area on your back on the
sides it's 3 in the profile that's going
to allow you to stay you know Mobile in
your hips as I was talking about earlier
and then in the front it has a 4in wide
profile that's going to you know really
you know give your abs you know give
your core right here in the front a nice
surface area for you to brace against
now when it comes to the cons honestly I
don't think there's any you know thing
really negative with this specific belt
it just you know boils down to personal
preference like I was talking about
earlier so you can definitely still use
this belt for your powerlifting
movements I personally do but you know
if you are you know a dedicated
powerlifter you're probably just going
to be better off going after a thicker
fully leather belt since it's going to
create you know more more a more rigid
feel and provide even more you know
external stimulus for you to
[Music]
brace have
faith have faith believe in your source
okay so the 6in reinforced lifting belt
from Iron bull is going to run you right
around $35 and honestly that's a pretty
average price tag when you go and
compare against the rest of the market
now yes there are going to be a few that
are a little bit cheaper they might be
cheaper for a reason that's you know
when it comes to Quality and quality
really isn't something that I think you
have to worry about with this specific
belt I mean the velcro is really nice
this self-locking rolling Buckle was
really nice and honestly just the
overall nylon build in general like I
said I've been using this for a while
it's really holding up you know that
original shaping and I can't really
notice anywhere and tear whatsoever so
yeah 35 bucks it's a pretty solid deal I
think it's going to last you a pretty
long
time okay so remember with this belt you
do have this reinforced backing right
here and you know it is nylon so you
know it is going to bend and Contour to
your body but with this you know extra
thickness and everything back here it's
going to create you know more stiffness
on your lower back which is definitely a
good thing especially as you start going
up in weight as you see you know you do
have this tapered design I really like
that I really like how it gets thinner
right here because it's going to allow
me to stay Mobile in my hips the front
is great for you know your abs and you
know U pressing up against it you know
and stabilizing your core and then once
again that back you know it's 6 in so
it's just going to give you a lot of
support on your lower back this is
available in six different colors
whether you want black like we have red
blue green gray or a gray camo there's
definitely an option for you and when it
comes to sizing so there's five
different sizes from extra small to
double XL whenever you go to do you know
sizing for yourself you want to measure
around your belly button and definitely
get you know a fabric measuring tape
like you would like a tailor for example
because it's really going to you know
fit around your body and give you that
accurate reading so iron bu has a full
sizing chart definitely check that out
and you know find the one that fits you
best okay okay but I mention you measure
around your belly button because that is
where the belt goes okay so it's where
you want it to go put it right around
your belly button and also I really like
this velcro strap especially paired with
this self rolling self-locking excuse me
rolling Buckle right there it's going to
allow you to really pull it tight and
then once you get it here split those
apart run it back
through sometimes it takes a second to
kind of get used to it but you're able
to really really pull it tight and get
that you know snug fit that you want now
don't do it too tight you want to be
able to you take your thumb and kind of
fit it in right there because you want
to have some extra room for when you
breathe and you know brace right so when
you're using a belt you don't want to
breathe vertically if that makes sense
you want to breathe out so you want to
expand in your stomach so you want to
and you can kind of see where my stomach
here I'll turn this
way you kind of see where my stomach is
sticking out right there and that's
going to allow you to really brace and
you know push against the belt and
create as much stability as possible so
definitely remember that so I think this
is a really solid all-around belt for
people who like to mix in their workouts
you know with Olympic lifting and
powerlifting when I talk about
powerlifting that's because you know you
do have this reinforced backing right
here and it makes it pretty stiff back
there which is going to be a really good
thing you know as you're going to lift
some heavy weight but since it is
tapered on the sides right here it's
going to and it's you know nylon it's
going to allow you to stay pretty mobile
and you know pretty stay pretty
explosive during those Olympic
weightlifting and Crossfit style lifts
which you know require you to be
explosive so you know if you're looking
for Best of Both Worlds for 35 bucks
this is a really solid option and
there's only two reasons to not purchase
this belt in my opinion the first one
being it's not ipf approved so if you
are looking for an ipf approved belt
ironbull has a lot of other ones you
might want to go check out and kind of
sticking with that kind of just boils
down to personal preference in your
style of lifting right so if you're a
dedicated powerlifter well you're
probably just going to want to go get
you know a thicker fully leather belt
and then if you're a dedicated you know
Olympic weightlifter and crossfitter
then you might not be too crazy about
this reinforced backing and just want to
go after you know a fully you know nylon
belt that doesn't have that so you know
whatever the case is ironbull probably
has an option that you might want to
check
out all right that's all I got for y'all
today on the ironbull 6in reinforced
lifting belt this is a really solid
all-around belt all right so this
reinforced backing works great for
powerlifting while the nylon build is
you know great for any explosive lift
you may be doing thanks for watching
y'all hope this video was really helpful
and I was able to break down everything
you need to know about this belt as
always stay posted for my next video but
for now head over to barn.com cuz we
have a full written article about this
belt you might find to be pretty helpful
all you got to do is search barbend Iron
bull 6in reinforced lifting belt review
it's going to pull right up for for you
you can go over every single thing I
talked about here today I'll catch you
next
[Music]
time